Hi, so we're ready for the third meditation
for the third week of this lam rim
course.
And in the last meditation we had done an
act of truth to send...
actually the whole thing we're trying to send
the virus to the middle of the sun
right?
And I like to think if our lam rim course
together... if we are successful
together, then something will happen to the
virus you know?
Maybe we can
contribute to stopping this problem in the
world, and it should be like that
right?
So let's try.
And we did an act of truth.
Act of truth requires some
ammunition.
Act of truth is like shooting a gun right?
And you need some kind of
ammunition; you you have to say "if it's true
I did this, then made this happen."
And we we said if it's true that I've shown
any small kindnesses... ok I've been
reading articles about someone who served
a hundred thousand meals in
hospitals, hooked up all the restaurants to
the hospitals, and served one hundred
thousand meals.
And I read another article about five physicians
from from my
old university and they're just doing extraordinary
things you know?
Huge
things that affect thousands and thousands
of people.
But people like you
and me, during this virus... not to go along
with the general fear, not to go
along with the general self-preservation instinct,
not to go out
and buy all the toilet paper on the first
day of the virus you know?
Try to
do small things for other people..
That's our ammunition.
So I guess that
means if you haven't done any small things
for other people during this
virus then let's get started.
All right?.
Just small good things.
Encourage
other people, give other people some hope,
share things with other people.
You don't
have to...
I read about a lady who made 30,000 masks
or something okay?
I'm
not talking about that, I'm talking about
identifying people who are scared, and
who are sad, and who are worried about the
future, and showing them some basic
human kindness okay?.
So that was our ammunition and then we
did an act of truth: If it's true that during
the
days of the virus, during the
time of the of the virus, I did this nice
thing to someone else--small
elegant nice thing--then blind people should
start to see, and hungry
people should be given a great meal, and sick
people should get better, people on
ventilators should all start breathing on
their own.
And even people who are
travelling in their cars, because they can't
go in a plane, they should be safe--
their car should work nice.
Children should be safe during this difficult
time..
Elderly people should be safe during
this difficult time.
People have trouble sleeping which is...
I haven't
seen any numbers but it's got to be a huge
problem right now.
Then we did
an act of truth and we sent that to those
people.
Now we're going to do another
act of truth okay?
This is the third meditation and we're shifting
gears.
We're still in the human realm..
We're still in the world of human beings.
We got out of the hell realms, animal realms,
hungry ghost realms, and we're
still dealing with troubles in this world,
during this virus.
[Master] Shantideva
makes a list okay?
So remember where we are--we're going to do
this meditation
now.
We're going to do an act of truth.
We're going to think about some, small beautiful,
elegant package of kindness we have delivered
during this
virus.
And we're going to make a mental statement
that "if it's true that I have
done this small kind thing then may may the
following things happen."
And then
there'll be a list of things that we want
to happen.
So here we go.
Get ready
to meditate okay?.
Take a drink of water.
And these meditations
are short, they're designed to be 15 minutes
only.
Something to do once or
twice a day.
So we're going to make it very simple.
We're going to get into the
meditation with ten breaths.
(DBUGS 'BYUNG RNGUB) Here we go.
Long exhales.
Keep exhaling
until the lower tummy tightens--which is more
than you usually exhale.
We're
going to do ten long breaths this way--long and fine.
Now please think about some small, elegant,
beautiful kindness you have paid
to someone during this difficult time in the
whole world who's afraid, worried
about the future.
And some small gesture you made to them, but
it should be real.
It should be something you really did.
And then say to yourself: "let's do an act
of truth: If it's true that during
this frightening time I paid one small kindness
to another person, then the
following things should happen."
Okay and here's our list from Master Shantideva's
chapter on dedication.
Number one..
People who are having obstacles with
their spiritual practice right?
These are deeper obstacles than not having
food or not having clothing okay?
At the beginning of this meditation session
we
showed a photograph of a young woman meditating
and people were making fun of
her.
So if it's true that I have paid some kindness,
then may obstacles to
people's faith, and wisdom, and love--may
these obstacles to their spiritual life
be removed
in this world.
If it's true that I did this one kind thing
during this difficult time, then
may everyone everywhere... and it's humans
everywhere in the universe,
may they have the freedom to practice their own spiritual path.
May they have this
freedom.
May they be free from interference in
their private spiritual life
and may they
be free from divisiveness inside
of spiritual practitioners.
May they have... enjoy some kind of unity
and harmony
within groups of spiritual practitioners,
and in general may they have the freedom
to follow the path they would like to try.
Here Shantideva adds another group of people.
These are people who have not
been able to practice well because of physical
needs.
They didn't have enough
food, they didn't have enough money, they
didn't have sufficient clothing, and it
actually damaged their body.
And that damage to their body also damaged
their
self-esteem.
So if it's true I have paid this kindness
to someone else, then by
this act of truth may people like that with
low self-esteem--
may they come to have great spiritual
practice.
And Shantideva here includes people who were
born into a society which has
different levels within that society, and
among those levels they were born into
the lower levels.
And they were taken advantage of, or they
were hurt,
systematically--by the system of their of
their culture and they were kept down.
May those people suddenly find the right and
the position to enjoy a deep
spiritual practice.
And by the way, I will take away the seeds
of bad thoughts,
words, and deeds done by any of these people
in the past okay?
That's similar to taking away illness from
a person.
Illness is what we call
"result suffering".
And the seeds for that are negative--being
negative in how you
speak, how you think, how you act.
So may this act of truth also remove suffering
in the form of pain which is about to come.
Things which are not pain yet--
pain which is waiting to happen.
If I've done this act of truth, may people
show loving conduct to each other.
May there be no darkness in their attitude
or their behavior.
May they be
perfectly innocent, and helpful, and kind
to each other.
May all spiritual practitioners, through my
act of truth, live a long life.
May they
feel experiences of bliss.
And then,
Shantideva ends this meditation very
sweetly.
May the word "death" disappear from this world.
May we come to a time in this
world where nobody knows what the word "virus"
means,
and nobody remembers what
the word "Covid" means.
And no one even remembers what the word "death"
used to
mean
because these things are gone.
If it's true I have shown some kindness
during this pandemic, then may these things
come to pass.
Then slowly open
your eyes..
Take a good stretch.
And we'll do this
meditation for a week
and then we'll pick
up with.
Master Shantideva next week.
Thank you.
thanks Tim.
Thanks
Seiji.